toontrack.com 2019-06-26

# Privacy policy | Toontrack

## OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Toontrack Music AB, company reg. no. 556105-8099 (“Toontrack” or “we” or “us”) recognizes that you care how information about you is collected and used. We have created this Privacy Policy to inform you of our information collection, use and sharing practices for this website, www.toontrack.com (the “Website”) and all of its sub domains. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered through this Website and, where applicable, through our Support Forum and Web-shop in connection with this Website or support for products you have purchased.

Toontrack is the data controller for the personal data collected by us on our own behalf.

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, you should contact us by e-mail at privacy(at)toontrack.com.  

#### WHAT INFORMATION ABOUT ME IS COLLECTED?

**Information You Voluntarily Provide**  
We collect and store information that you enter into this Website and Webshop or that you provide to our Support Forum. For example, information will be collected when you open an account, when you register and/or authorize a product, when you place an order, when you sign up to receive emails or other promotional communications, when you contact us with online enquiries and/or when you otherwise voluntarily submit or provide information to us. The information we collect that you provide to us includes: names, billing address, e-mail, telephone number, order history, IP-address, serial numbers of purchased products, identification number(s) used to identify certain hardware in your computer(s), any arbitrary identifying name or number you provide of the computers on which products are installed.. This information is used to complete transactions and provide the products and services that you have ordered or requested, and for administrative and analytical purposes. This information also may be used to contact you about sales, product updates, product recommendations and special offers, if you have accepted to receive communications in connection with this Website.

The table below shows the personal data collected from you by Toontrack, and the purpose of it. Toontrack may also use personal data when required by law.

**Purpose** | **Types of processing** | **Categories of personal data** | **Legal basis**  
---|---|---|---  
In order to fulfil obligations according to the purchase agreement | 

  * Administration of the customer relationship and payments.
  * Communications concerning support matters and responding to questions submitted to our support in order to provide assistance and support in accordance with the purchase agreement.

| 

  * Name
  * E-mail address
  * Telephone number
  * Address
  * Serial/identification numbers
  * IP-address

| Performance of the purchase agreement.  
In order to improve and develop our service | 

  * Customer survey

| 

  * Name
  * E-mail address
  * Previous orders

| Processing is necessary pursuant to the legitimate interests of Toontrack to develop and improve the its service.  
In order to prevent disruptions in our service | 

  * Evaluate and prevent disruptions and problems in the service.

| 

  * User name
  * IP-address

| Performance of purchase agreement.  
  
**Information We Automatically Collect**  
Like many Websites, we use technologies to collect and store certain other information automatically whenever you interact with this Website. For example, we may collect your IP address, browser information and reference site domain name when you visit this Website. We also collect information regarding customer traffic patterns and site usage. This information is used to analyze and improve this Website and to provide our customers with a fulfilling experience.

Also, like many Websites, we use “cookies”, which are files stored on your computer’s hard drive by your browser. Cookies help us to identify account holders and to optimize their log-in, account management and shopping experience. Cookies also allow us to hold selections in a shopping cart when a user leaves this Website without checking out. Most browsers accept cookies automatically but allow you to disable them. We recommend that you leave cookies “turned on” so that we can offer you a better experience on this Website.

We may from time to time also use pixels, transparent GIF files, Flash movies or other visual surfaces to help manage online advertising. These files enable our ad management partner(s) to recognize a unique cookie on your Web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our website. The cookie was placed by us, or by another advertiser who works with our ad management partner(s). With cookies, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address.

We may also collect information about the device you are using when accessing the Website or the Web-shop, including what type of device it is, what operating system you are using, device settings, unique device identifiers, and crash data. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you are using and its settings. To learn more about what information your device makes available to us, please also check the policies of your device manufacturer or software provider.

When you visit the Website, you will be informed about the information being collected and you may accept to provide this information to Toontrack. If you choose to decline, no such information will be stored but the Website may then not function correctly and Toontrack may not be able to provide its services to you. You have the possibility to manage cookies and other types of local data storage through your web browser. You also have the possibility to change your settings on your mobile telephone regarding data collection and sharing, e.g. location services and other data. Toontrack cannot control these choices or influence the basic settings since they are offered via mobile operators or web browsers.

**Other Information**  
We also may collect and store information about you that we receive from other sources, such as a postal service providing notices of change of addresses and providers of consumer data, to enable us to update and correct the information contained in our database and to provide product recommendations, updates and special offers that we think will interest you.

**Storage time**  
Toontrack only saves your personal data for as long as necessary for the purpose of the respective personal data process, or as long as necessary according to law. Information that is no longer necessary is deleted.

**How and where Toontrack stores your personal data**  
Toontrack processes your personal data within the EU/EEA since Toontrack’s servers are located within the Area. This means that your personal data will not be transferred to third countries. Toontrack approaches security with the utmost seriousness. Toontrack uses several methods to protect the information you provide to the company. Toontrack strives to ensure that your information will not disappear, be unlawfully used, end up on the wrong hands and is not exposed. The methods used to secure your information take into account modern technology as well as how integrity-sensitive the information is which Toontrack collects, manages and stores. If you wish to know more about Toontrack’s policy regarding security and confidentiality for your personal data, we encourage you to read our Data and Security Policy.  

#### IS INFORMATION COLLECTED FROM CHILDREN?

We do not sell any items ordered through this Website directly to anyone who we know to be under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, you should not use this Website to submit orders or purchase any items. In addition, we do not collect online any personal information from anyone who we know to be under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, you should use this Website only with the involvement of a parent or guardian and should not submit any personal information of any kind to us. Contact Toontrack if you discover that a child under 13 has provided personal data without the approval of their guardian.  

#### WITH WHOM DOES TOONTRACK SHARE INFORMATION?

We do not share with others any personal information that you provide to us through this Website or through our Support Forum, except with your consent, when required by law or as described in this Privacy Policy.

We engage third parties from time to time to perform services in connection with the operation of our business. Examples of these services include, but are not limited to, development, operation and maintenance of our Website, management of customer accounts, payment processing and authorization, fraud protection and credit risk reduction, product customization, order fulfillment and shipping, gift card processing and management, marketing and promotional activities, Website evaluation, data analysis and, where applicable, data cleansing. We may provide personal information to these third parties, but we authorize them to use this information only in connection with the services they perform on our behalf. We may permit such third parties to disclose personal information to subcontractors, but only if the third party limits the subcontractor’s use of such information to services performed on our behalf.

We also may offer you the opportunity to purchase products and services provided by or in conjunction with third parties. If you purchase any of these products or services, we may provide your personal information to the third parties that provide the products and services that you request, but we authorize these third parties to use this information only in connection with the products and services they provide. We may also provide information, including personal information, about you to certain business partners, but only if you participate in programs offered by such business partners.

We may share non-personal information with our marketing partners, advertisers and others from time to time. Examples of such non-personal information include the number of users who visited this Website during a specific time period or purchased a specific product through this Website. This information is shared in an aggregated form.

We may use information that we collect from visitors to our Website to remarket certain products that believe that are of particular interest or benefit to individual visitors. We are implementing our remarketing efforts through the use of third-party software and services. When we are using these services, our third-party service providers may display banners and ads on other websites that our visitors may visit. These third-party service providers will more than likely collect information using cookies. You can remove these cookies by contacting those third-party service providers or disabling them on the third-party service providers’ websites. The information collected with respect to our remarketing activities will typically be maintained in our third-party service provider accounts and will be subject to the third-party service providers’ privacy policies. The visitor information that is maintained in certain of our third-party service provider accounts will be deleted thirty days after it has been collected but some third-party service providers may maintain it for shorter or longer periods of time.

We, or those with whom we have shared information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, may release personal information if we believe in good faith that: the law or legal process requires it; we have received a valid administrative request from a law enforcement agency; or such release is necessary or advisable to protect the rights, property or safety of Toontrack, or any of our respective affiliates, business partners, customers or others. We may also disclose personal information to assist us in the collection of amounts owed by you to us or to one of our business partners with whom you have authorized us to transact business on your behalf.

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you, including personal information, in connection with the sale or transfer of all or a portion of the business or assets of Toontrack to a third party. We also reserve the right to share the same information with any Toontrack subsidiary or affiliate.  

#### YOUR RIGHTS

You have the following rights in accordance with applicable data protection legislation:

  * The right to access. You can request a copy of the personal data which Toontrack has collected and stored about you in its capacity as personal data controller. You may request a copy at no charge.
  * The right to rectification. You are entitled to have incorrect information rectified by Toontrack or to supplement incomplete information.
  * The right to erasure. You are entitled to have your personal data erased provided the information is no longer necessary for the purposes of processing, if you object to direct marketing, if the personal data has been processed in an unlawful matter, or where the personal data must be erased in order to fulfil a legal obligation covering Toontrack.
  * Right to restrict processing. You are entitled to request that Toontrack’s processing of your personal data be limited.
  * The right to object. You are entitled to object to the use of your personal data for the purposes of direct marketing or in those cases in which Toontrack process your data based on a legitimate interest.
  * Right to data portability. You are entitled to request that your personal data processed by Toontrack about you as a consequence of fulfilling the customer agreement is transferred to another personal data controller.

The Swedish Data Protection Authority (Sw: Datainspektionen) is responsible for monitoring the application of the data privacy legislation and, if you believe that Toontrack is processing your personal data in an improper way, you have the possibility to file a complaint with the Swedish Data Protection Authority.  

#### WHAT STEPS ARE TAKEN TO KEEP PERSONAL INFORMATION SECURE?

We use various security measures that we believe are customary in our business to protect personal information that we collect. If you place an order through this Website or our Web-shop, you will be asked to set up an account and provide an email address and password. You must provide an appropriate email address and password in order to access account information. In order to help protect your personal information further, you should not provide your password to others. If you wish to cancel a password, or if you become aware of any loss, theft or unauthorized use of a password, please contact our Support Department by email at support(at)toontrack.com or by phone at +46(0) 902001820.  

#### CAN I INDICATE WHETHER OR NOT I WANT TO RECEIVE COMMUNICATIONS?

To stop receiving e-mails from us, login to your account on our Website and change the settings in your user details. You also will have an opportunity to change these settings by clicking on an hyperlink contained in the e-mails we send you.  

#### WHAT HAPPENS WHEN I LINK TO OR FROM ANOTHER WEB SITE?

This Web site may contain links to other Websites operated by Toontrack and/or Websites operated by third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to information gathered through these other Websites.

If you have accessed this Website through a link from certain of our advertising or marketing partners, this Website may include a frame of the applicable advertising or marketing partner. Nevertheless, the information you provide to us through these framed Webpages is collected by us, and our use of this information is governed by this Privacy Policy.  

#### INTERNATIONAL USERS

The Website and the Web-shop are primarily hosted in Sweden but parts thereof may also be hosted on servers located in other countries. If you access the Web site or the Web-shop from the North America, South America, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from those of the EU, please be advised that through your continued use of the Website or the Web-shop, you are transferring your personal information to Sweden or any other country and you consent to that transfer. Additionally, you understand that your personal information may be processed in countries (including Sweden) where laws regarding processing personal information may be less stringent than in your country.  

#### HOW WILL I BE INFORMED ABOUT CHANGES REGARDING THIS PRIVACY POLICY?

Our Website will continue to evolve to bring you new features and services and to implement technological advances. As a result, we may change this Privacy Policy from time to time without prior notice. Revised versions of this Privacy Policy will be posted on this Website, together with an updated effective date. In some cases, we may also send an e-mail notifying users of the changes. You should check this Website periodically to see if any recent changes to this Privacy Policy have occurred. By continuing to use this Website after we post any such changes, you accept the Privacy Policy as modified.  

#### EFFECTIVE DATE

This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 25, 2018.

We use cookies to give you the best possible service. If you continue browsing, you agree to the use of cookies. Read more I accept
